HENRY TOTTLE

Full Stack Developer

CONTACT

**** 07709 772422

★ henrywilliamtottle@gmail.com

Q Bath, Somerset

portfolio

FULL STACK TRACK

iO Academy

During the intensive 16 week course I have quickly picked up and developed fundamental skills required to be a full stack developer. I am competent with GIT, PHP, Javascript, Node, HTML and CSS as well as frameworks including Slim, Express, React, BootStrap and Tailwind. I have learnt to appreciate the value of Object Oriented Programming, and I enjoy the efficiency of routing. I also have experience testing with jest and PHPUnit.

- Gained Agile certification
- Acted as scrum master twice, with a team of 8 and a team of 3.
- Complete 7 projects:
 - o Portfolio HTML, CSS
 - Collection App PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS
 - Film Quote Game Javascript, HTML, CSS
 - Job Site React Project React, JS, Bootstrap
 - Furniture Store API OOP, mySQL
 - CRUD To Do MVC, Slim, PHP
 - o Academy Portal Slim, JS, MVC, PHP

PROFILE SUMMARY

Enthusiastic and approachable full-stack developer recently graduated from iO Academy and based in Bath. Coming from a background of audio engineering and bookselling, my time not spend coding is balanced between reading, guitar and more importantly spending time with my family. Throughout my career I have been the go to tech support person and taking a leap into software development has been a dream in the making.

PROJECTS

Subscriptions Assistant - Full Stack

An app to assist in the role of book subscriptions to help make informed decisions about what book to pick each month. The app fetches data from both Google Books API and Open Library to help populate information on each title where available. It has **CRUD** features, tags can be created and deleted, and book lists can be imported from CSV.

Front end is build with **React** with **React Router** and **TailwindCSS**, back end with **PHP & Slim 3** and **SQL** with **RESTful API**.

GITHUB -FE | GITHUB -BE | Live Version

Furniture Store API

We built an API using well structured **Object Oriented Programming** in PHP in combination with **SQL** queries to both populate and access a local database. This worked alongside a pre-existing Front End React project. During this project I acted as **scrum master** and worked on populating the database as well as creating service classes for unit conversion and currency conversion and updating the burn-down chart.

GITHUB | Live Version

EDUCATION

2024

FULL STACK TRACK

iO Academy

2010 - 2013

MUSIC AND SOUND TECHNOLOGY BSC HONS

University of Portsmouth

2007 - 2008

A LEVEL - CHEMISTRY, PHYSICS, MUSIC TECHNOLOGY

King's College Taunton

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

Agile Certified 2024 BSAC Sports Diver - 2006

HOBBIES

- Obsessing over guitar tone
- Reading Science Fiction
- Occasional Half Marathons

JOB HISTORY

Systems & Training Lead

Mr B's Emporium of Reading Delights

In this role I was responsible for providing IT solutions to colleagues and customers alike. To improve efficiency within the team I started work on a bible of documentation for the many and varied processes and software that was used to keep the back of house running. In this capacity I also worked as the onboarding contact for the new members of the team. Other responsibilities include creating ticket sales spreadsheets for events, using and manipulating sales data for informed buying and being an approachable and communicative member of the team to support the shop floor.

Library Support Assistant

2016-2017

2017-PRESENT

University of Bristol

S

Working within the relegation project team, ensuring the correct books and serials were removed from library space with attention to detail, and delivering them to the research reserve where they would be correctly catalogued and shelved for future use. This included careful time and workload management to work around the various time frames of each library department and working both autonomously and as a team.

Library Support Assistant	University of Bristol	2016-2017
Deputy Regional Commercial Manager	Waterstones	2015-2016
Senior Bookseller	Waterstones Wells	2013-2015